Reanimation Jutsu: Release!"
（ゲンマ）よし　追い詰めた。
All right! We've cornered him!
《意識が戻ったと思えば
このざまか…》
Just when I thought
I regained consciousness,
this happens…
何だ！？
What's that?!
《マキ：やはり手ごわい。　パクラ先生》
You're strong, after all…
Pakura Sensei.
（パクラ）マキ。
Maki…?
（マキ）パクラ先生！
Pakura Sensei?!
（デイダラ）出せっつってんだろ！
Let me out!
もうキレた！
堪忍袋の緒が切れた！
I've had it! I'm completely fed up!
いいかげん爆発すっぞ！　うん！
I'm gonna explode, hmm!
いいのか？　こら！
You okay with that, huh?
（カンクロウ）
お前が爆発できねえように→
We got you sealed
with the Lightning Style,
こっちは雷遁かましてんだ。
especially so you can't explode.
ふかしてんじゃねえよ。
いろいろと不発野郎が。
So shut your trap! You dud!
（デイダラ）芸術に不発はねえんだよ。
There are no such things
as duds in art!
Huh?!
まさか　爆発！？
No way, an explosion?!
何だ！？
What is it?!
（チヨ）これは…。
What is this?
（チョウザ）ダンさん。
Dan!
（ダン）ああ。　どうやら
誰かがうまくやったようだ。
Yeah. Looks like someone succeeded.
（ビー）ナルト！
人柱力たちが消えそうだ。
Naruto! The Jinchuriki are
gonna quit it!
どうやら　イタチが
うまく　やったようだ。
Looks like Itachi did it!
《ナルト：ありがとう　イタチ》
Thanks, Itachi!
（ビー）こっちは　まだ　うだう～だ。
But this battle ain't going anywhere!
うだうだ言ってねえで
こっちもやるってばよ。
No time to waste! Let's go!
オオノキに言え。
Tell Ohnoki…
忍連合の行く末を見届けてから→
He must secure the future of
the Allied Shinobi Forces…
俺に伝えにこい…　とな。
Only then can he come
and tell me all about it…
いったい何が？
Just what the hell is going on?
そうか。　あのインテリ
やられやがったな…　うん。
I get it…
The bookworm's been
taken down…hmm.
不発じゃん。
びっくりさせやがって。
It was a dud.
Don't scare us like that.
（デイダラ）ドッカ～ン！
うわっ！
不発なんかじゃねえ！
It wasn't a dud!
芸術は　不滅だ～！
Art is…
indestructible!
脅かしやがって。
Scaring us like that…
あっ　チヨバア。
Granny Chiyo!
いまいましい呪縛から
ようやく解放されたようだな。
Looks like I'm free
of the cursed spell.
パクラ先生！
Pakura Sensei!
マキ　つまらぬ死に方をするなよ。
Maki, do not die in vain!
先生…。
Sensei…
お前たちには　未来がある。
You all have a future…
（チヨ）どうやら
やっと死ねるようじゃな。
Looks like I can finally die…
チヨバア！
カンクロウ…。
Granny Chiyo!
Kankuro…
傀儡師の技　しかと託したぞ。
I entrust you with the techniques
of the Puppet Master.
受け継いでいきます…　チヨバア。
I accept and will take it over…
Granny Chiyo.
死んだフリも　これで終わりじゃ…。
No need to play possum anymore!
思ったとおり…。
As expected, I can control
my body freely now.
もう　意志どおりに体を動かせる。
結界を解いてくれ　チョウザ…。
Choza, please undo the barrier.
もう　大丈夫だ。
It's safe now.
…のようですね。
It seems that way…
皆　結界は　もう必要ない。
Everyone, there's no need
for the barrier.
はっ！
Right!
チョウザ…　すまなかった。
Choza, forgive me.
その印　霊化の術ですね…
わかってます。
Those signs are for the Ghost
Transformation Jutsu, aren't they?
I understand.
早く　綱手様のところへ
行ってあげてください。
Please hurry to
Lady Tsunade's side!
多くの忍を殺めてきた
この術が…。
This jutsu has killed so many shinobi…
まさか　こんなふうに役立つとは
思いもしなかったよ…。
I couldn't have imagined that
it would come in handy like this!
霊化の術！
Ghost Transformation Jutsu!
思ったとおりだ。
Just as I thought!
穢土転生解放後の　昇天する魂も→
Souls ascending after being released
from the Reanimation Jutsu
この霊化の術なら
コントロールできそうだ。
can be controlled with this jutsu too.
でも　時間は
あまり　ありそうにないですよ。
But it doesn't seem like
you have much time.
急いでください。
ああ…。
Please hurry!
Yeah…
じゃあな　チョウザ…
いろいろ　ありがとう。
Farewell, Choza!
Thank you for everything!
す　すごい…
霊体のまま　飛んでった…。
Amazing…
He flew off like a ghost!
霊化の術って　いったい…。
Just what is the Ghost
Transformation Jutsu?
生き霊となって→
It allows one to become
a living ghost
距離を越えて相手にとりつき
殺す術だ…。
that can span long distances
to kill a foe…
本来はな。
Originally, that is.
《綱手…》
Tsunade…
((里の未来のために
改革は必要なんだ。
Reform is necessary for
the future of our village.
犠牲になる者を
少しでも減らすために。
In order to keep the lives sacrificed…
to a minimum.
（綱手）そのとおりね…。
You're right.
手伝ってくれるかい　綱手…。
Help me, Tsunade.
私でよければ…。
If I can be of help to you…
キミが必要なんだ。
I need you.
ダン…。
Dan…
一緒に　夢を叶えよう！
Let's make our dreams come true!
(うん…))
Yes.
《忍の夢を…》
Our dreams as shinobi.
（青）これは…　どういうことだ？
What's going on?
穢土転生体のチャクラが
次々に消えていくぞ！
Reanimation chakra is
fading steadily!
（いのいち）各地の部隊から
報告が上がってきている。
We have reports coming in
from each battlefield.
穢土転生体が　昇天していると…。
The reanimated are turning
into souls.
封印されたのも…
活動しているのもだ！
Even the sealed ones,
even ones still fighting!
（シカク）状況から判断すれば→
The only way to explain
the situation is that…
the Reanimation has been released…
穢土転生が解除された…
ということになるが。
間違いない！
穢土転生の術が解除されたんだ！
There's no mistake.
The Reanimation Jutsu
has been released!
よし！
このことを全部隊に伝えてくれ！
All right!
Relay this news to every company!
本部より連絡。
穢土転生は解除された。
Reporting from Headquarters.
The Reanimation has been released.
繰り返す。　穢土転生　解除だ！
I repeat!
The Reanimation Jutsu
has been undone!
すごい！
みんな　消えていっている！
Amazing! They're all disappearing!
しかし…　いったい
どの部隊が　やり遂げた？
But…
Which company managed to do this?
（イタチ）俺のことを
ずっと許さなくていい。
You don't ever have to forgive me.
お前が
これから　どうなろうと…。
And no matter what you do
from here on out…
俺はお前を　ずっと愛している。
I will love you always.
（サスケ）俺は…。
I…
ユギト　やぐら。
Yugito…
Yagura…
ハン　ウタカタ。
Han…
Utakata…
フウ　ヒゲのじいちゃん！
Fuu…
Old Man Beard!
任せろってばよ！
Just leave it to us!
行っちまいやがったな。
They're gone.
《…てぇことは　他の戦場も…》
Then this means
the other battles are…
《マダラ：カブトめ…　失敗したか》
Curse Kabuto, he's failed.
よそ見してんじゃねえよ！
Hey, what are you looking at?!
You're fighting me!
お前の相手は　この俺だ！
（ガイ）碧き野獣もだ！
As well as the Green Beast!
（カカシ）穢土転生は
解除されたようだな。
Looks like the Reanimation
has been released.
それが…　どうした？
And…
what of it?
（メイ）あの光は…
いったい何なんです？
What is…that light?
（オオノキ）スサノオが消え
更に　穢土転生の塵あくたが→
The Susano'o is gone and now…
the debris from the Reanimation
is in a fierce whirlwind.
激しく舞っておる。
これは　間違いなく…。
Without a doubt, this means…
穢土転生が
解放されたということだな。
The Reanimation has been released.
（エー）何だと！？
What?!
カブトは　まだ捜索中のはず。
早すぎる！
We haven't located Kabuto yet.
It's too soon!
Even if Kabuto was found,
to be able to stop this jutsu…?
発見しただけならともかく
この術まで止めるとは…。
いったい誰が？
Who could have done this?
誰でもよい。　誰であろうと
忍世界を守った英雄じゃ。
It doesn't matter!
Whoever did it is a hero
who's saved the Shinobi World!
天は　まだ　わしらを見放しては
おらんようじゃぜ。
The heavens haven't forsaken us yet!
It appears you have able shinobi
on your side too.
（マダラ）お前のそばにも
やれる忍がいたようだな。
しかたない。
It can't be helped…
（メイ）覚悟した？
まだじゃ！
He was prepared for this?
Not yet!
消える前に１発
くらわせようという腹じゃ。
He's planning a final strike
before he disappears!
気をつけい！
Watch out!
火遁　龍炎放歌の術！
Fire Style: Dragon Flame Caterwaul!
《水遁…
いや　間に合わない！》
Water Style…
No… It won't make it in time!
（綱手）ぐっ！
火影様！
大丈夫！
Lady Hokage!
I'm all right!
《百豪の術が　切れたか！？》
The 100 Healings Jutsu has worn off!
《だが…　勝った…》
But…
we've won…
しまった！
Damn!
ん？　今のは？
What was that?!
I thought she completely
lost consciousness!
完全に
意識を失っていたはずじゃ。
《私は　もう動けなかった。
どうして？》
I couldn't move anymore…
So how?
((ダン：久しぶりだな。　俺だ　綱手。
It's been a long time…Tsunade.
ダンだ。
It's me, Dan.
ダン！　なんでここに？
Dan… How are you here?!
穢土転生が解かれたんだ。
The Reanimation has
been undone.
で　霊化の術で飛んできた。
And I flew over here with
my Ghost Transformation Jutsu.
しかし　今のは危なかったよ。
But that was a close one!
ダン…。
Dan…
変わらないね　綱手。
You haven't changed at all…Tsunade.
ダン！　私は　ずっと　あなたの…。
Dan…
I have always honored your…
時間がない。
感傷に浸っている暇はないんだ。
There's no time to wallow
in sentimentalities.
もう行かなくちゃいけない。
I have to go.
そんな…。
But…
戦って　大切な人を失うばかりが
忍の仕事じゃないよ。
Fighting and losing
precious people…
is not all there is to
being a shinobi.
俺は　里も仲間たちも大好きだ。
I love this village and my comrades.
だから守りたい。
みんなを守る存在。
So I want to protect them.
A person that protects everyone…
火影は　俺の夢だから。
Becoming the Hokage
is my dream.
ダン　私は　あなたが死んでから→
Dan!
I ran from my memories
of you for a long time,
ずっと
あなたの想いから逃げてた。
after your death.
でも変わった！　そして今なら→
But I've changed!
And now…
あなたの無念を
やりたかった想いを→
I can confirm with you
what all your regrets
もう一度　確かめられる！
and the things you wanted
to do were!
私は　火影になった。
I've become the Hokage!
でも…。
ありがとう　綱手。
But…
Thank you, Tsunade.
キミは　俺のやりたかったことを
十分　成し遂げてくれているよ。
You are fulfilling my dreams
for me just fine.
キミには　つらい思いばかり
させてしまったね。
I really caused you a lot of pain.
ごめん。
I'm sorry.
向こうで待ってる。
I'll be waiting for you on the other side.
でも　当分は来ないでくれよ。
But don't come too quickly, okay?
キミは　俺の夢　そのものだから。
For you yourself are my dream.
最後に　キミを守れたんだ。
I was able to protect you at the end…
(穢土転生されたかいも
少しはあったかな))
It appears a little bit of good did come
from being reanimated.
火影　無事か？
Hokage, are you all right?!
（マダラ）生気が戻ったな。
チャクラをもらったか？
Your vitality has returned.
And you received chakra?
ちょっと
昔の知り合いに会ってな。
I got to see an old friend
for just a little while…
すぐにまた会うことになる。
Well, you'll meet again right away.
（メイ）何？
いったい　どうなっているの？
What? What's going on anyway?
離れかけていた
マダラのチャクラが→
Madara's chakra which had begun
しっかりと
体にへばりついている。
to separate from his body
is now clinging firmly to it.
元に戻った？
Is he back to his original state?
なぜだ？　なぜ消えない？
Why? Why won't he disappear?!
穢土転生は　解除されたはずだ！
I thought the Reanimation
was undone!
穢土転生とは
死者を口寄せする術だが→
Reanimation is a jutsu that
summons the dead.
ただひとつ　リスクがある。
However, there is one risk…
（我愛羅）リスク？
Risk?
（マダラ）それは
印さえ知っていれば→
As long as one knows the signs,
穢土から呼ばれた死人側から→
the reanimated dead can
rescind the Reanimation Contract
穢土転生の口寄せ契約
そのものを→
from their end.
解除できるということだ。
契約を解除だと？
Rescind the contract?!
そうなってしまえば
これほど厄介なことはない。
When that happens,
you end up with
the biggest problem of all.
死なぬ体　無限のチャクラ。
An immortal body with infinite chakra…
that can move without control.
それが制御不能で動き出す。
まさか…。
Impossible!
術者に言っておけ。
Tell the jutsu caster…
禁術を　不用意に
使うべきではないとな。
Never use a Forbidden Jutsu carelessly.
穢土転生　解！
Reanimation, release!
《一族とは　何だ？》
What is a clan?
《里とは何だ？》
What is a village?
《忍とは　何だ？》
What is…a shinobi?
俺はいったい…。
What am I?
（水月）み～つけた！
Found you!
お前ら…。
You guys…?
（水月）よっと　こんなとこで
何やってたの？
What're you doing here?
穢土転生を止めていた。
は？
Stopping the Reanimation.
Huh?
キミ　昔からそうだよね。
You've always been like that.
人に　ものをちゃんと
説明しようって気ないよね。
You never explain things to people.
でも　久々に会ったんだから
ちゃんと説明してもらうよ。
Well, it's been awhile
since we saw you,
so you'd better tell us!
何？
What?
カブトだ。
It's Kabuto…
Huh?
カブトが　穢土転生を使っていた。
Kabuto was using the Reanimation.
How… How can that be…?
こんな…
こんなことって…。
この程度の術で縛られる
俺ではないことは→
Your ridiculously juvenile jutsu
can't hold me.
戦っているお前らなら
納得がいくはずだが？
You should know that
after fighting me, right?
さて　スサノオ完成体→
Now then…
The Perfect Susano'o…
あれを一度　目にした者は
死ぬといわれている。
Everyone who sees it dies…
or so they say.
一度　引っ込めてしまった以上→
I'm almost embarrassed
to have to do this again.
二度も出すとなると
少し　みっともない。
I already used it once…
邪魔が入って　興がそがれた。
My interest has waned,
thanks to the interference.
そろそろ　九尾を
取りにいってもいいのだが。
Perhaps I ought to go
retrieve Nine Tails instead.
なんじゃと！？
What?
((こっちのマダラは
わしらに任せい。
Let us deal with this Madara!
必ず　ケリをつける。
I swear we shall finish him off!
(ここは　安心して
わしらに任せろ))
So relax and leave him to us!
Lord Tsuchikage!
土影様　もう私たちでも→
We cannot stop him.
太刀打ちできる
相手ではありません。
We still have to fight!
それでもやるんじゃ！
ここで　こいつを止めねば！
We must stop him here!
So sad…
醜いな。
（カカシ）雷伝！　ガイ！
おう！
Lightning Cable!
Guy!
Right!
くらえ！　小指攻撃！
Take this! Pinky Attack!
はあ～っ！
Heh! You don't look too happy!
へっ　苦しそうな顔してんな。
どういう意味だ？
What's that supposed to mean?
顔　隠してっから　俺が勝手に
そう思って見てんだよ。
Since you're hiding your face,
I can only guess.
If you feel insulted,
take off that mask
悔しかったら　面とって→
and show us how composed you are!
余裕顔かましてるとこ
見せてみろってばよ！　バーカ！
Stupid!
ふん！
いいぞ　ナルト！
Nice going, Naruto!
はぁ…　相手をあおるなと
言ってきたのに。
I told him not to rile up his opponent.
Well… It seems I have
no choice but to use it.
しかたない。
やらざるをえんか。
あれは！
え？
What is that?!
A giant gourd and a bottle…
でっけえひょうたんと
壷だってばよ。
本当なら　完全な状態で
復活させたかったのだがな。
Frankly, I wanted to revive this
when the conditions were perfect.
It's only a fragment,
but it's not lacking in
しかし　かけらでも
その力に変わりはない。
もう　ずいぶんと遅い
約束の時間だ。
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手
１０組の皆さんによる→